Persuasion is a drama, romance, tv movie film directed by Adrian Shergold.
Living with her snobby family on the brink of bankruptcy, Anne Elliot
is an unconforming woman with modern sensibilities.
When Frederick Wentworth – the dashing one she once sent away – crashes back into her life, Anne must choose
between putting the past behind her or listening to her heart when it comes to second chances.
Anne Elliot, played by Sally Hawkins.
Captain Wentworth, played by Rupert Penry-Jones.
Lady Russell, played by Alice Krige.
William Elliot, played by Tobias Menzies.
Sir Walter Elliot, played by Anthony Stewart Head.
Elizabeth Elliot, played by Julia Davis.
Persuasion is a 2007 British historical romance television film
adaptation of Jane Austen's 1817 novel Persuasion.
It was directed by Adrian Shergold, and the
screenplay was written by Simon Burke.
Sally Hawkins stars as the protagonist Anne Elliot, while Rupert
Penry-Jones plays Captain Frederick Wentworth.
Eight years before the film's beginning, Anne was persuaded
to reject Wentworth's proposal of marriage.
Now 27 and unmarried, Anne re-encounters Wentworth, who has made his fortune in the Napoleonic Wars and is
looking for a wife—anyone but Anne, whom he has not forgiven for rejecting him all those years ago.
Persuasion was one of three novels adapted in 2007 for ITV's Jane Austen Season.
It was the first of the three adaptations to begin development.
The drama was co-produced by Clerkenwell Films and American studio WGBH Boston.
Persuasion premiered on 1 April 2007 in the United Kingdom
and was watched by 5.4 million viewers.
Persuasion received positive reviews from television critics.
The film explores themes of navy, based on novel or
book, love triangle, poetry, love.
The tone is emotional.